blackdesertonline.com 2019-04-30

# Black Desert Online Login

**Privacy Policy**

We at Kakao Games Europe B.V., a Dutch company registered with the Dutch Trade register under no. 62780476, having its registered office at Handelsweg 59J 4th Floor, 1181 ZA Amstelveen, The Netherlands (hereinafter, “Kakao Games Europe” or “we”), take the protection your personal data seriously. That is why we ensure that your personal data is secured and monitored against abusive use and access by unauthorized parties. This document (hereinafter: “the Privacy Policy”) is intended to provide you with simple and accurate information about the personal data we collect, how we collect the personal data and for what purposes. Your rights with regard to the collected personal data are also mentioned in this Privacy Policy.

Before using our services please read carefully this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, do not use our Services.

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. In such event, we will notify you either with an official announcement on our website www.blackdesertonline.com (hereinafter: “the Website”) or with an email sent to your registered email address. Announced changes will only come into effect after a reasonable period of time. You can reject the updated Privacy Policy by stop using our Website.

Data protection officer contact details:  
You may contact our data protection officer (KyuMan Lym) using the contact details below:  
by email at privacy@blackdesertonline.com  
or by phone at +31 (0) 6 43 70 64 70 

**What means “personal data”?**

Personal data means "any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person” ( [Article 4 (1) of the General Data Protection Regulation (hereinafter: “GDPR”)](https://gdpr-info.eu/art-4-gdpr/)).

**What personal data do we gather about you and how, when you visit the Website?**

We collect personal data in order to improve your experience at our Website. We also process data that you leave on our website. The Website uses "Cookies". These are small files that get saved on your computer and enable the analysis of your use of the Website. The data about your browsing behavior collected by the cookie usually gets sent to the Google servers in the US and is saved there. We do this to gather information about the pages users visit on our Website, to keep track of how often users come back and to see which pages are doing well on the Website. We also keep track of what information the browser shares. We do this online using the following tools and cookies:

**Google Analytics**

The website uses Google Analytics. This allows us to gain insight into how our site is used. This means, among other things, that we understand how you and where you are on our website. To obtain this insight, we collect and process data about your use of the website, your location from which you use the Website, your IP address and information about your browser and operation system.

When you access our website, a banner is displayed informing you which cookies will be installed if you continue browsing on our Website. If you continue browsing or click on "I agree" on the banner, you are giving your consent to use Google Analytics.

The collected and processed data expires after the end of the browser session and after two years from set/update.

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics cookies on all the websites you visit, please go to https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en

**Functional Cookies**

We use functional cookies. The functional cookies we use are session ID cookies. These cookies are necessary for the proper functioning of the Website. For example, we use cookies to log in and respond. The functional cookies allow us to keep your account session open while you browse. This means that you do not have to log in at every page again.

Your consent is not required for such cookies. Please note that session ID cookies are required for the proper functioning of our website.

Data collected and processed: IP address, browser information, date and time.

The collected and processed data expires after the end of the browser session if you have not checked the "Stay logged in" box when you signed up on our Website. If you checked the box 'stay logged in' the cookies expire after 24 months.

**Third Party Cookies**

We use tracking cookies. These third party cookies follow individual behavior on our website. It creates profiles, for example to enable targeted advertisements. The tracking cookies also collect data relating to the traffic to the website. We use this information to determine how our site is found and used to ultimately improve your experience on our website.

We also use Facebook Pixel. Facebook Pixel is a tracking code cookie provided by Facebook. It allows us to track which advert brought you to our website and which pages you visited on it. It helps us to make our advertisement campaigns more efficient.

In addition we use social media functions. This provides us anonymous data that we can analyze to find how our information is shared outside of the website. These cookies are used to collect anonymous statistics and performance data.

When you access our website, a banner is displayed informing you which cookies will be installed if you continue browsing on our Website. If you continue browsing or click on "Got it!" on the banner, you are giving your consent to use the cookies.

You can remove cookies. You do this by changing the settings of your browser. At the bottom of this Privacy Policy you will find an instruction how to remove Cookies.

**Personal Data Storage Period**

Personal data of customers are normally stored permanently.  
When a customer requests to delete his/her account, the personal data of the relevant customer will be stored for 2 years in order to handle any civil services.

**What personal data do we collect when you play a game on our Website and for what purposes?**

When you decide to play a game on our Website, you have to create an account. The following data is processed when you create an account.

_Name;_

_Username/Nickname;_

_Email address;_

_IP address;_

_Date of birth;_

*For users who have signed up through Steam or Facebook, the UID used for authentification of the relevant platform will be stored.

This information is used to identify your account. It allows us to let you make in game purchase, access the offered games, request customer support and assist you if you lose your password. We use the data also to inform you about our product range, to improve our services and fix bugs. We do not sell your information to third parties for commercial purposes. We may also use your IP address in order to generate anonymous statistics about our player base.

 When you play the game that services provided by us, following data is processed.

_Session information;_

_IP address;_

_MAC address;_

_Hardware information._

This information is used in order to:

_Provide you customer support when you request it;_

_Verify that you do not violate the terms of service;_

_Generate anonymous statistics about our player base;_

_improve the game experience._

Your anonymous hardware information (to the extent that you cannot be directly or indirectly identified based on such information) is not personal data and we do not sell your information to third parties for commercial purposes. 

**What personal data we collect and process when you buy a game package or “Kakao Cash” for the virtual item shop?**

Your billing information allow us to properly process your order, provide you customer support if required, comply with taxes and maintain business records. We require billing information for any transaction you perform on our website. The following data is processed for billing purposes:

_Name;_

_Address, including City, State and Country;_

_Payment method information._

Your billing information are collected and processed by third parties who provide us billing services (Global Collect, Paypal, Payletter and Paymentwall). We will keep a copy of your billing data as well as the API key for the relevant payment method. We keep the collected data for the duration required by law for billing documents. 

**Will Kakao Games Europe send me newsletters as soon as I have registered my email?**

Yes, Kakao Games Europe will send you newsletters with relevant developments on the platform, game updates, offers or other relevant information for our users. The frequency depends on these factors. Whether or not you agree to receive newsletters can be changed on myinfo page on the website. Upon withdrawing from the agreement to receive newsletters, any provided date will be destroyed.

**Handling personal data in order to resolve CS requests**

In order to process CS request,   
authorization process of the individual will be performed. The personal data used   
to authenticate the identity of the customer will be deleted within 7 days after   
the CS request is resolved.

**Handling personal data for event winners**

IPersonal data of the customer may be collected in order to distribute the reward related to an event promotion. This personal data will be deleted at the point of receipt for the reward, or this personal data may be encrypted and stored if this data needs to be rechecked to omit any duplicate wins for recurring events.

**Who do you share my personal data with? And where do you store my data?**

All personal data we have collected from you is accessible only to duly authorized employees of Kakao Games Europe for the purposes stated in our Privacy Policy.

External companies or natural persons to the extent that such access to your personal data is required to provide you with the various services you require, and provided that a confidentiality agreement has been signed in advance to ensure the confidentiality of your personal data;

Legal authorities, law enforcement agencies or a natural person if we are legally required and / or have received a request to provide the data;

All relevant emergency services or law enforcement agencies if we think your health or safety is at risk;

All subsequent legal entities, in the case of a merger, acquisition, consolidation, sale or transfer of assets, or any event that affects the company and that requires us to transfer control over user data, provided that such a transfer is made authorized by applicable law and required for the performance of the envisaged transaction.

All personal data is stored on our servers located in the European Union.

**Kakao Games Europe may share personal data of customers for the following reasons:**

Partners and Service-providing agencies  
Kakao Games Europe may share information in order to improve upon service, process payments, and send newsletters.

**Affiliates**

The content of the ticket may be shared in order to handle customer service.

**What are my rights?**

You have the following rights:

**Right to be informed**

To ensure fair and transparent handling of personal information, Kakao Games Europe must inform its Customers on how their personal information is being used. If the Customer requests information on how his or her personal information is being used, Kakao Games Europe must provide the relevant information in a simple and straightforward manner. Customers may make these requests through Customer Service.

**The right of access**

You have the right to obtain confirmation from us as to whether personal data concerning you has been processed by us. You also have the right to access the personal data and information about (inter alia): the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned, the recipients or categories of recipients to whom the data have been or will be disclosed.

**The right to rectification**

You have the right to obtain the rectification if the personal data that we have processed from you is incorrect or inaccurate. We will correct your personal data without undue delay.

**The right to erasure (the right to be forgotten)**

You have the right to obtain the deletion of your personal data if one of the reasons stated in [ article 17 GDPR](https://gdpr-info.eu/art-17-gdpr/) applies.

**The right to restriction of processing**

You have the right to obtain verification from us if one of the reasons mentioned in [ article 18 GDPR](https://gdpr-info.eu/art-18-gdpr/) applies.

**The right to data portability**

You have the right to receive the personal data that concerns you that you have provided to us. You receive the data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. You also have the right to ask us to transmit this data to another controller.

**The right to object**

You have the right to object to the data processing if the data processing takes place on the grounds referred to [Article 6 (1) (e) or (f) GDPR](https://gdpr-info.eu/art-6-gdpr/). We will no longer process the personal data unless we are able to demonstrate convincing legitimate interests for the processing that exceed your interests, rights and freedom or when this is necessary for instituting, exercising or defending legal claims.

**The right to lodge complaints with the Dutch Data Protection Authority (“DPA”)**

You have the right to lodge a complaint about the processing of your personal data at the Dutch DPA. According to [Article 57 of the GDPR](https://gdpr-info.eu/art-57-gdpr/), the Dutch DPA is obliged to handle all complaints it receives.

**Right to related to automated decision making and profiling**

In the case of when an issue may have major repercussions such as issues which require legal action, the Customer will not be affected by decisions which are based on automated systems such as profiling. In these cases, the Customer may request a withdrawal of such decisions.

If you have questions about this privacy policy or your rights, please contact us. You can reach us at the following e-mail address: privacy@blackdesertonline.com

Effective Date:  May 23, 2018

Last reviewed: March 1, 2018

**Appendix - How to remove cookies:**

**Internet Explorer:**

Launch Internet Explorer; at the top-right open the Internet Options Menu; on the General tab, select Delete, in the Browsing History Section; select the Cookies check-box, and click the Delete Button.

**Chrome:**

Open Chrome; at the top-right, click Settings; at the bottom click “Advanced”; in the 'Privacy and security' section, click Content settings; under “Cookies”, click “All cookies and site data”; at the top-right, click “Remove all”; at the bottom-right, click “Done”.

**Opera:**

Go to 'Settings'; Select “Preferences; Select “Advanced”; select “Cookies”; click on 'All cookies and site data'; there you can click on 'Delete all'.

**Firefox:**

Click the menu button and choose Options; Select “Privacy and Security”; under History, set Firefox will: to Use custom settings for history; click “Show Cookies”, the Cookies window will appear; In the Search: field, type the name of the site whose cookies you want to remove. The cookies that match your search will be displayed; select the cookie(s) in the list to remove and click Remove Selected.

**Safari:**

On the Safari Menu, click on 'Preferences'; select 'Privacy'; set your preferences for accepting cookies next to 'Block Cookies'; select 'Parties and Advertisers' - 'Always' or 'Never'; if there are any website data/cookies being stored, click 'Details’; to remove specific data, highlight the information and click 'Remove'; to remove the data from all the sites, click 'Remove All'.
